<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startup | Tommy Chan's software blog (@tommytcchan)]]></title>
  <link href="http://tommytcchan.github.com/blog/categories/startup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tommytcchan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-06T23:39:13-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://tommytcchan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tommy Chan (informotion software)]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[tommytcchan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get into a tech accelerator: A co-founder's story]]></title>
    <link href="http://tommytcchan.github.com/blog/2014/02/06/how-to-get-into-a-tech-acclerator-a-co-founders-story/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-06T22:53:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tommytcchan.github.com/blog/2014/02/06/how-to-get-into-a-tech-acclerator-a-co-founders-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our startup <a href="http://venuespot.co">venuespot.co</a>, based out of Vancouver, Canada was recently <a href="http://500.co/2014/02/03/batch-8-announcement/">announced</a> in an offical 500startups post. We are 1 of 28 companies selected out of 1400+ to get a chance to be in Silicon Valley along with Dave McClure and his managing partners. Since then, a lot of my friends and ex-coworkers have asked me how we were able to achieve that. I want to dedicate this post to founders who aspire to get into tech acclerators. Keep in mind though that your milage may vary, but I think this will be a good read for those who inspire to participate in one.</p>

<h1>Our Story</h1>

<p>My business partner and I, Jerome, met during start up weekend last year. We immediately got along and started chatting about what we did. Right off the bat I can tell that he was a driver and a go-getter. Unfortunately for him, at that point in time I wasn't too interested in his idea. It was only after a few months later when we saw each other again at another start up weekend that I got to work closer with him. By then the business plan had pivoted into something that excited me. I myself is an event organizer for a local tech meetup group, and the idea of not having to waste time to look for a venue for my meetup excited me. It would be a system where you would tell the system what you wanted, and a bunch of algorithms would be used to match the venues that would be suitable for the event, and the system would send notifications to the matching venues which they would then place offers to host the event. It was in June of last year that we started working together and it took 3 good months of product development to get to a stage where we can show it in front of venues and event organizers.</p>

<h1>The road to 500starups</h1>

<h1>Here's a few personal tips on how to get into an accelerator.</h1>

<blockquote><p>Be that jock in high school.</p></blockquote>

<p>No I don't mean go and work out 3x a day for the next year. What I mean is that you should be the 'popular' dude in high school that all the girls wanted. You see, the biggest fear of investors is that they will lose out on what turns out to be the next Facebook or Twitter. If they hear that another investor is investing in you, they would want to invest first. So you have to play that card to your advantage by hyping yourself up. The way we did that was we basically interviewed first with the 3rd tier accelerators, got letter of intents from them, then went to the 2nd tier accelerators (and told them we got accepted into the 3rd tier accelerator), also got intents from them, and then with those letters of intent, went after the top tier accelerators. The results were what you'd expect: after the first term sheet, we had no issues with getting a second, and a third, and then a fourth. We eventually decided on the fourth term sheet because it gave us the most connections to the big names.</p>

<p>That was the first strategy which worked pretty well. I don't believe that was 100% of the reason why we got in. There's also another reason:</p>

<blockquote><p>Have connections into the accelerators before you meet the managing partners.</p></blockquote>

<p>Think about it. If you were an interviewer for a position, would you want to hire someone who handed their resume through a site like Monster.com, or would you want to hire someone who was referred by someone you know and trust? One of the things I found was that the tech circle is very small, and that nowadays it's sooooo easy to find connections via either social media or Angelist. If you can't find someone you know that knows a managing partner at an accelerator, then in my opinion you should not deserve to be in an accelerator. For our strategy, we volunteered at a Techcrunch conference which gave us a chance to also meet a lead into the 500startups family, and that was another reason we were able to catch the attention of the partners at 500.</p>

<blockquote><p>Teamwork is everything.</p></blockquote>

<p>The partners at the accelerators want to know that your team can execute. No matter what, all the members of the team should be present at the interviews. All of the accelerators that gave us term sheets mentioned that we have a great team. There's no doubt in my mind that we do but we certainly need to show the partners that we can work well together and execute as a team. Ideally you and your co-founder(s) should have been working for over 6 months.</p>

<h1>Conclusion</h1>

<p>To conclude, I think it is imperative that if you want to get into an accelerator, you need to follow a few good rules of thumb. That being said, nothing beats cold hard numbers. If you are getting millions of downloads per month then they might take exception to that. But for the rest of us, if you try to follow the 3 pieces of advice that I gave you, then your chances of getting accepted has just dramatically increased.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
