<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: acclerator | Tommy Chan's software blog (@tommytcchan)]]></title>
  <link href="http://tommytcchan.github.com/blog/categories/acclerator/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tommytcchan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-17T23:57:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tommytcchan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tommy Chan (informotion software)]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[tommytcchan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experience in a Tech Acclerator - Halfway Point]]></title>
    <link href="http://tommytcchan.github.com/blog/2014/03/17/experience-in-a-tech-acclerator-halfway-point/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-17T22:16:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tommytcchan.github.com/blog/2014/03/17/experience-in-a-tech-acclerator-halfway-point</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week marked the halfway point of being in batch 8 of the 500 startups tech acclerator. Our company <a href="www.venuespot.co">VenueSpot</a> has entered the accelerator in January and I want to take a moment to reflect at this point, both in terms of my personal life and work life.</p>

<h1>The Highs</h1>

<h2>The Batchmates</h2>

<p>Being in a pressure cooker environment with 30+ of your peers who are also trying to make it would scare quite a few people. However, it's quite contrary to what you would think. People are super nice in the batch and will go out of your way to help you in any way they can. When we drove down from San Francisco, we didn't have anywhere to stay. One of the batch teams actually offered us their space (a shutout to the guys at <a href="www.remarkhq.com">Remark</a>). We stayed there for about 2 weeks while we looked for an apartment nearby. So I would say that this experience has been made a lot better with the batch mates.</p>

<h2>The 500 Network</h2>

<p>500 startups has an extensive network of people who are either directly involved in 500 and it has really been a great learning experience. We've had people coming in from all over town -- Paypal, Microsoft, Trulia, Twilio, Pinterest, AirBnb, Prominent VCs such as Paul Graham. We got a bunch of great advice on such as how to measure your KPIs, tips on UI/UX, and stories of early days from founders. We have barely scratch the surface as my co-founder is now in the process of connecting with other folks from the network as we raise an advisory round with preferred market cap.</p>

<h2>The Tech Community</h2>

<p>Being a technical co-founder, I've always being jealous of all of the great things happening here in the valley. Coming down to the valley makes me realize what I've been missing. I go to a lot of meetups in Vancouver but it's nothing compared to the numbers of meetups here. It really is the epicenter of technology, so it really is no wonder why everyone comes here. The people here are super smart and for an aspiring developer, this is the place you should be.</p>

<h2>The San Francisco Weather</h2>

<p>Coming from Vancouver, Canada, it was really a treat for us to experience the great sunny weather that we've been having. It really boosts morale when you are walking to work with nothing but blue skies.</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/static_garage/2014-02-19%2008.49.40.jpg" alt="Sunny SF" /></p>

<h1>The Lows</h1>

<h2>The Distractions</h2>

<p>Coming into the acclerator, I didn't really know what to expect. I mean, we were working 70+ hours a week and I didn't think that was going to change. That is still true to this date (we probably work about 80+ hours a week right now). So that wasn't unexpected. What was unexpected though was all the distractions that you have being an acclerator. There is a whole bunch of things that happen throughout the week. One of the advice that was given to us was that you can spend all your time in the acclerator going to meetups and events, so you really have to focus.</p>

<h2>Weeks of Desolation</h2>

<p>Coming into the acclerator, we realized it was going to be tough for us to be in San Francisco where we don't have a presence, and sure enough it felt like the you have the weight of the world on your shoulders. This was true especially in week 4. 1/3 of the acclerator was over, and we were scratching our heads in terms of what to do. We barely had any traction in the new city and we were stressing out about the looming deadline (aka Demo Day) in May. I remember having a conversation with my co-founder about pivoting to something completely different. I think it's one of those things that every team goes through ("Are we building the right thing for our customers? Is it a problem that people actually care about?"). It's super stressful when you're in that situation and you hear that another company in your cohort is making $20,000 dollars a day.</p>

<h1>The unexpected</h1>

<h2>The fire</h2>

<p>Last week was one of the craziest weeks of my life. We started of the week feeling great (more on this in the vitamins section). We were getting some traction and we have developed a better vision in terms of the next steps. Then the fire happened. If you don't know what I mean, do a search on SF fire on Google News. It was a freakin' <em>6 alarm fire that happened right across the street!</em> It was the biggest fire in over a decade, and it happend 30 feets in front of our apartment. Honestly it was the craziest thing (see below for images). At first, being the pyro that I was, I was hoping it would keep burning and burning (I know I need some psychological help)...but then I saw a picture which show the apartment next to it and I quickly realized that it was our building. At that point I realized we were in a heap of trouble as our 2 dogs Oreo and Kandi were trapped inside. So we quickly took a cab and had the guy drop us off as close as possible. We got to the door and was quickly confronted by the police who told us to stay back. After multiple pleas we were able to be escorted by an officer into the building...while we were running into the building I was thinking how close we were to the fire...we can literally feel the fire on our faces. When we entered the building it was like the scene of a movie...smoke everywhere, water running everywhere, firefighters yelling. It felt surreal. Luckily we got the dogs out and we were all safe. We did have to stay at Remark's place for a few more days (thanks Remark!).</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/static_garage/2014-03-12%2021.35.47.jpg" alt="The fire" /></p>

<h2>The food made with love</h2>

<p>After my co-founder and I settled in, we quickly realized that we were eating a lot of crappy food that we were used to. That's because my awesome wife wasn't there. Our health got a lot better after I flew to Seattle to pick her up (so we could both drive down). She's our cheerleader and I'm really grateful for that.</p>

<h2>The vitamins</h2>

<p>I have to admit, we've had really long days and I was really tired...but after experimenting with vitamins and supplements I feel a lot better. Maybe it's a placebo effect but I've experienced a lot more energy. I do say it's not the best experience though (I have to pop 7 pills at one time, once a day). I would recommend this to all future founders that work long days. Maybe it's just me but the vitamins and the 5-HTP makes me feel happier.</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/static_garage/2014-03-17%2023.18.46.jpg" alt="The vitamins" /></p>

<h2>The fun times</h2>

<p>There are so many awesome things to do in SF. If only we had enough time to do them all. Some of the highlights were (in no particular order): going to the Napa Valley for wine tastings, a night out in the Mission district with the lovely wife, drunken nights with the crew, talking about trannies among other things =).</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/static_garage/2014-02-16%2014.51.30.jpg" alt="The fun" /></p>

<h2>The psychic abilities</h2>

<p>I believe that since I've moved down here, I've developed a form of energy that I can't explain. Every time I have a headache, an act of nature happens. The first time I had a headache here, there was a 6.9 earthquake 500km away from San Francisco. The second time I had a bad headache, the next day the crazy fire happened. And get this...I had a slight headache last night, and the first thing this morning was an earthquake in Los Angeles (&lt; 500km away). What's going on here? I'm sure to blog about it the next time I have a headache.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
